<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-12-21T18:56:53-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Home</title><subtitle>Peronsal Resume and Portfolio.</subtitle><author><name>Alexander Nordin</name></author><entry><title type="html">Automating Prediction Problem Generation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/edge%20case/MEng-Thesis-Work/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Automating Prediction Problem Generation" /><published>2017-09-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-09-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/edge%20case/MEng%20Thesis%20Work</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/edge%20case/MEng-Thesis-Work/">&lt;p&gt;I’ll be spending the next year working under Kalyan Veeramachaneni at the Data to AI Lab at MIT. Two years ago, a student wrote a thesis detailing a language to formally define prediction problems. In the coming year I’ll extend his work and build out a fully functioning system to generate prediction problems from a given dataset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Machine learning has seen a swell of activity in recent years. Many applications of machine learning involve industry-specific tasks where acquired data is leveraged to build classifiers that can better predict events. Today we have an abundance of data and a need for more machine learning experts to perform analysis and derive insights. We’ll call data analysis the process of a machine learning expert analyzing data. One major impediment to the data analysis process is coming up with relevant prediction problems that can be answered with the data. We propose a system that can automatically generate prediction problems. Incorporating our technology into the data analysis process will greatly reduce the barrier to entry for understanding and advantageously using machine learning for data scientists and laymen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the full thesis proposal:&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alexander Nordin</name></author><category term="content" /><category term="css" /><category term="edge case" /><category term="lists" /><category term="markup" /><summary type="html">I’ll be spending the next year working under Kalyan Veeramachaneni at the Data to AI Lab at MIT. Two years ago, a student wrote a thesis detailing a language to formally define prediction problems. In the coming year I’ll extend his work and build out a fully functioning system to generate prediction problems from a given dataset.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Neuroscience Research: Queensland Brain Institute</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/post%20formats/Neuroscience-Research/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Neuroscience Research: Queensland Brain Institute" /><published>2017-07-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/post%20formats/Neuroscience%20Research</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/post%20formats/Neuroscience-Research/">&lt;p&gt;I spent 7 weeks performing neuroscience research with Geoffrey Goodhill and his team at the Queensland Brain Institute. The team had recently collected a dataset with neural information about zebrafish. The zebrafish dataset contained precise information about activation levels of every indivudal neuron in the zebrafish’s brain. We used this data to investigate spatial and temporal relationships within the zebrafish brain. Through in-depth, rigorous analysis I discovered no significant temporal relationship in zebrafish’s brain activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a full report on my work:&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alexander Nordin</name></author><category term="Post Formats" /><category term="readability" /><category term="standard" /><summary type="html">I spent 7 weeks performing neuroscience research with Geoffrey Goodhill and his team at the Queensland Brain Institute. The team had recently collected a dataset with neural information about zebrafish. The zebrafish dataset contained precise information about activation levels of every indivudal neuron in the zebrafish’s brain. We used this data to investigate spatial and temporal relationships within the zebrafish brain. Through in-depth, rigorous analysis I discovered no significant temporal relationship in zebrafish’s brain activity. Here’s a full report on my work:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Using Sentiment to predict the Market</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/edge%20case/Market-Sentiment/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Using Sentiment to predict the Market" /><published>2017-05-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-05-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/edge%20case/Market%20Sentiment</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/edge%20case/Market-Sentiment/">&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine, Dillon Dumesnil and I worked on a project to predict the direction of the S&amp;amp;P500’s price using information scraped from twitter.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Alexander Nordin</name></author><category term="content" /><category term="css" /><category term="edge case" /><category term="lists" /><category term="markup" /><summary type="html">A friend of mine, Dillon Dumesnil and I worked on a project to predict the direction of the S&amp;amp;P500’s price using information scraped from twitter.</summary></entry></feed>